<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science of Gifts</title>
    <description>Use science to find the best gifts for everyone.</description>
    <link>http://scienceofgifts.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://scienceofgifts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 22:13:54 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 22:13:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>27 Inexpensive Yet Charming Christmas Gifts for Coworkers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12511268/10633181/bfc035da-7806-11e5-934a-44f886b013d5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;horrible_bosses&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not your success depends on how you get along with your coworkers. The better relationship you have with them lesser the stress and more job satisfaction. Studies show that people who get along well with their colleagues are more productive than others. So you see, you have to do something nice for them every once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a present is not mandatory, it doesn’t hurt to give one. After all, who doesn’t like gifts? The real conundrum is that you need to get them a nice present, and yet not put a dent in your back balance. To help you do that I have put together a list of the best yet inexpensive gifts that you coworkers will love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gadgets&quot;&gt;Gadgets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to giving a gift, inexpensive, little, useful gadgets are the best. Everyone loves them (Especially men), they fit in small boxes, and they make your life easier in some way (Which is what everyone wants). Hence they top my list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flashlights---699&quot;&gt;27) Flashlights - $6.99&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12511268/10637349/c32b0292-7822-11e5-8922-2dc38401672f.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;flashlight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A flashlight at hand is always a good idea. Most people misplace them or never think of getting one and use their cellphone flash instead, which aren’t that bright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These little flashlights are amazingly bright and they come in handy during blackouts or Ninja attacks. Those sneaky Ninjas rely on darkness to attack you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give these to your coworkers and they’ll use them in darkness and associate you with light in the dark. A Rescuer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005FEGYCO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B005FEGYCO&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=giftscie-20&amp;amp;linkId=WS5JHASU26JAZXQX&quot;&gt; LE Adjustable Focus CREE LED Flashlight, Super Bright, Batteries Included - Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=giftscie-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B005FEGYCO&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alarm-clock-radio---1699&quot;&gt;26) Alarm Clock/ Radio - $16.99&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12511268/10637494/a031c982-7823-11e5-9c9f-d552edbfdd14.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;radio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those regular alarm beeps, they wake you up, but they’re boring. Wouldn’t you like to wake up to the sound of radio. Someone yapping somct/B00IEYHMIM/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00IEYHMIM&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=giftscie-20&amp;amp;linkId=VWJZNZ74INVUVNXT”&amp;gt;Sony ICFC1 Alarm Clock Radio, Black&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=giftscie-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00IEYHMIM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bluetooth-transmitter---1999&quot;&gt;25) Bluetooth Transmitter - $19.99&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12511268/10637539/e41439e6-7823-11e5-8900-895c676b0a18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bluetooth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how it’s late and everyone’s asleep and you have to keep the volume painstakingly and inaudibly low?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this sweet piece of electronics is the solution. You can connect it to the audio output of your TV and you can use your Bluetooth headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see how useful they are? Don’t you love technology?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men love these kinds of gadgets. They are also very simple to use and last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00GKEAQ2M/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00GKEAQ2M&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=giftscie-20&amp;amp;linkId=GOMQJGFRVFTSFPLN&quot;&gt;Bluetooth 4.0 Transmitter TaoTronics Wireless 3.5mm Adapter Dongle (High-Fidelity Stereo, Plug and Play via USB or AUX Input, Charging while Playing for TV &amp;amp; iPod)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=giftscie-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00GKEAQ2M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;touch-2-car-mount-holder&quot;&gt;24) Touch 2 Car Mount Holder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12511268/10638849/ac583082-782a-11e5-8100-2d664d861e4d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mounter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to save lives? OK, that may be a little dramatic, but you could save someone’s life by giving them one of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we get distracted by the phones and take our eyes of the road to receive a call or text, which is dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Car mounters allow you to have your phone mounted easily in front of you so you can watch the road while operating the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00JRGOKQ8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00JRGOKQ8&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=giftscie-20&amp;amp;linkId=PUXHCRHK6JR7Q53W&quot;&gt;iOttie Easy One Touch 2 Car Mount Holder for iPhone 6s Plus 6s 5s 5c, Samsung Galaxy S6 Edge Plus S6 S5 S4, Note 5 4 3, Google Nexus 5 4, LG G4-Retail Pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=giftscie-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00JRGOKQ8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tablet-mount-holder&quot;&gt;23) Tablet Mount Holder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12511268/10638880/d530f7a0-782a-11e5-8d9f-29db11d4352c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tablet mounter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It says car mounter, but you shouldn’t be using tablets while driving. Why would you even need it? But you can use it at home, may be in the kitchen–mount your Ipad and watch stuff like Youtube videos while cooking. I think you could try placing it in the bathroom. Watch movies while in the tub, like a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why didn’t I think of this before? Yeah, I’m going to buy this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was ranking these gifts, this would be top the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NIVGNE0/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00NIVGNE0&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=giftscie-20&amp;amp;linkId=BWANJKQMNZRGE6KW&quot;&gt;iOttie Easy Smart Tap 2 Universal Car Desk Mount Holder Stand Cradle for iPad Air 2, iPad Mini 3, Samsung Tablets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=giftscie-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00NIVGNE0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bluetooth-car-kit&quot;&gt;22) Bluetooth Car Kit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thing allows you to control some of your phone’s features without touching the phone–like play/pause music, volume control, shuffle songs, and even activate Siri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just have to connect it to your phone via Bluetooth and connect an audio output like headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s especially useful to those with large phones since they could just use this to play music without handling the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great gift for music lovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lipstick-size-power-bank&quot;&gt;21) Lipstick Size Power Bank&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Power banks are great. Thank god for them (A lot of movies wouldn’t have lasted long if the character in trouble with a dead phone had one), but you can’t just carry them in your pockets. Or can you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is the size of a lipstick. You can just put it in your purse and take it wherever you go. I think James Bond had one of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of this is, you can gift it to anyone with a smartphone. They’ll love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mugs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mugs make fine gifts since they can be personal. If you know the person and his likes, hobbies, and favorites, you can gift them one and they’ll know you put some thought into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which you must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also you can be creative and funny, even something that is a private joke between you and your colleague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an amazing variety of mugs out there, so you can buy different kinds for everyone–from science joke mugs for geeks to Game of Thrones mugs for, well, Game of Thrones geeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;constellation-mug&quot;&gt;20) Constellation Mug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constellations appear when you put hot liquid in it. It looks beautiful, and also you know when your coffee is getting cold, so that’s a perk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people are interested in constellations, and they’ll like this mug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you’re bored, you can just observe and learn the formations. Show off your knowledge to people. Or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-lines-of-literature-mug&quot;&gt;19) First Lines of Literature Mug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mug has first lines from the best works of literature. Give it to someone who loves to read and they’ll love you. If someone gifted this to me, I’ll be their best friend in a moment. You so get me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mug is beautiful. The text is finely print with attractive fonts, and the color selection is lovely. Just reading the lines makes me nostalgic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you give it to someone who doesn’t read, they’ll read the first lines and be curious as to what the story behind the lines is and end up reading the books. Wouldn’t you love that? Turning someone into a reader? 
Gift it to your kids if you have any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thermo-lens-mug&quot;&gt;18) Thermo Lens Mug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few utilities of this mug. Here are some I could think of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) You can take it to places where food items are not allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b) It’s steel, so you can’t break it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c) It looks cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;d) You can hide things in it, like candies and chocolates. (&lt;em&gt;winks&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say gift it to a photographer, but everyone owns a DSLR these days, so works for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mathematical-formulas-mug&quot;&gt;17) Mathematical Formulas Mug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warning: For geeks only! Might elicit depressing math related memories in some people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could gift it to people who like mathematics, or The Big Bang Theory fans, or people with professions involving mathematical formulas such as programmers, scientists, teachers, or engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;harry-potter-mug&quot;&gt;16) Harry Potter Mug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work places can sometimes be stressful, you’d rather be in Hogwarts learning magic and kicking ass at Quidditch, so this message from Hogwarts will help get your spirits up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the Muggles get you down, dear wizard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your know someone who’s a fan of the Harry Potter series, you can gift them this mug. They’ll like the joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to send it with the owl. That’s how we roll at Hogwarts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-of-thrones-mug&quot;&gt;15) Game of Thrones Mug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the members of the nights watch only. Winter is coming and we need coffee to keep us warm. We need to stay awake for wall duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your coworkers are fans, you probably already know. Just don’t give it to someone rooting for the Lannisters, or white walkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoiler Warning: Do you think he’s alive? I think he’s dead, but will come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drinking-horn-tankard---this-is-how-warriors-take-their-drinks&quot;&gt;14) Drinking Horn Tankard - This is how warriors take their drinks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just look at it. It looks so medieval. You might as well get a huge fireplace and share legends with friends while sipping your Viking coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s big, sturdy, and stylish. It will be a great addition to anyone’s coffee mug collection. Especially Game of thrones or Viking fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let them celebrate Christmas Viking style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jane-austen-mug&quot;&gt;13) Jane Austen Mug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no lack of Jane Austen fans in the world. If you know your coworker is a fan, give them this mug on Christmas and they’ll love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the movie The Rewrite Keith Michaels (Hugh Grant) gifts Mary Weldon (Allison Janney) Jane Austen goodies to make amends with her. And it woks, at some level. She, being a Jane Austen admirer, loves it and eventually forgives him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cute-cat-mug---wrap-in-a-nice-wrapurrr&quot;&gt;12) Cute Cat Mug - wrap in a nice wrapurrr&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously for cat owners. Just don’t give it to a dog person. It comes in black too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks cute with the pointy ears, and dots for eyes, and the long whiskers, like a grown up Hello Kitty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black version sort of looks like Catwoman in her childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shakespeare-insults-mug---thou-coworker-shall-love-this&quot;&gt;11) Shakespeare Insults Mug - Thou Coworker Shall Love This&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular insults are so cliche. Shakespeare insults on the other hand are trending. Or they will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s covered with the most funniest insults from the great playwright’s works. Making this the funniest gift in the list. I bet your coworker will crack up after seeing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thou art a boil, a plague sore.” It’s hysterical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also you can always use some Shakespearean insults in case you run out of regular ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friends-central-perk-mug---things-to-live-by&quot;&gt;10) Friends Central Perk Mug - Things to live by&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has some wise insights on it like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your friends are the family you chose for yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re never too old to dress up for Halloween.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s fine to spend Friday nights in your pajamas playing board games.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t get pressured into getting married too young. Or ever.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Friends fan got to have one of these. This mug reminds you memories from the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say give it to your friends too. No Friends fan cannot not love this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Cool Stuff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t want to gift the gadgets above or mugs, you can always go for the following options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tool-bag---so-that-you-look-like-you-can-fix-things&quot;&gt;9) Tool bag - So that you look like you can fix things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool bag is perfect as a Christmas present because of many things. It’s stylish, very functional, you can put most things you’ll need to carry around for minor jobs, there is even a loop to hang a hammer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that for a reasonable price, and it fits waist sizes 29-Inch to 46-Inch, so it’ll work for most people. It’s hard to find such attractive and functional tool bags. They’ll love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wall-mounted-key-rack&quot;&gt;8) Wall mounted Key Rack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something you give to a coworker you know not much about. Everyone owns keys, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s made of steel, it’s durable and inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is of coffee design but they come in various shapes and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also it’s small and stylish. Very gift like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;natural-air-purifying-himalayan-salt-lamp---feel-better&quot;&gt;7) Natural Air Purifying Himalayan Salt Lamp - Feel better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is trending. Apparently it releases negative ions into the air and creates an ionizer like effect and purifies the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll feel the difference in your mood when you turn it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These also make good show pieces. They come in different sizes, from seven to eleven inches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rick-grimes-bobble-head---the-wobbling-dead&quot;&gt;6) Rick Grimes Bobble Head - The Wobbling Dead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is hilarious. You’ll never get used to seeing Rick Grimes’s head wobbling. That’s so not Rick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your coworkers are a fan of The Walking Dead they’ll like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re one, imagine how cool will it look on your desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also others in the collection. Daryl Dixon with his crossbow, Michonne with her samurai sword, and even Merie with his hook arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazon-fire-tv-stick---more-netflix-for-everyone&quot;&gt;5) Amazon Fire Tv stick - More Netflix for everyone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connect this stick to your TV and you’ll have access to services like Netflix, Amazon Video, HBO GO, Hulu, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is pretty sophisticated, and has much better features than Chromecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take it with you wherever you go and watch your shows on any TV, whether you are in a hotel, or a friend’s place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can gift it to any TV watching, Netflix streaming coworker, and you’ll make their life more TVfull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kindle-fire-7&quot;&gt;4) Kindle Fire 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Fire 7 inch tablet is pretty great for it’s price. It’s got a lot of features and decent performance. Good for surfing the web, watching videos, and reading books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tablet is a bargain for your money. The battery lasts up to 7 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a gift under $50, consider this tablet. Plus, there is an offer going on in which if you buy five of these you get one free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kindle-hd-6&quot;&gt;3) Kindle HD 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one has a 6” HD display with over a million pixels (252 ppi / 1280 x 800). Great for watching videos. The sharpness of the screen makes surfing a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a $100 price tag it’s a good deal. Also, there is a number of colors to choose from, so you can get different colors for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m telling you, it’s the best tablet out there for that price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-new-kindle&quot;&gt;2) All new Kindle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Kindle is basically a 6” portable personal library. You can load thousands of books in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kindle was created for readers. There is no back-light, so it’s like reading from a paper. You can read for hours without your eyes straining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery lasts for weeks. There are many features which enhance your reading experience, like inbuilt dictionary, word wise, highlight. You can look up words on Wikipedia. There is also a vocabulary builder app which stores the words you looked up in the dictionary, so you can revise them later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best gift ever for readers if they don’t already own one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kindle-paper-white&quot;&gt;1) Kindle Paper White&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kindle is same as the Kindle above except with one additional feature. Light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, unlike tablets, it doesn’t have back light, rather LEDs from the side put light on the paper and not on your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit more costlier than the regular kindle which doesn’t have a back-light so you have to use external light sources in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 23:37:20 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://scienceofgifts.com/inexpensive-gifts-for-coworkers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://scienceofgifts.com/inexpensive-gifts-for-coworkers</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
